# Leo Rondeau

# Software Developer

#### **TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE**

## Nashville Software School - Teacher's Assistant

May 2021

Volunteer position for introduction to software development class.

- Tutored students on web development basics
- · Kept track of students progress
- · Guided students through building their first website

## Nashville Software School - Junior Software Developer

Sept 2020-Mar 2021

Intensive six month software development bootcamp with immersive, lab based learning and simulated work environment

- Full stack single page CRUD application development
- · State management through React hooks
- · Server side development using Python-Django
- · Employed ERD's, wireframes and dependency graphs for planning
- · Chrome development tools and debugger for troubleshooting

## **PORTFOLIO**

## Nashville Hot Heat Index

https://github.com/leorondeau/nashville-hot-react

Nashville Hot Heat Index is a single page full CRUD application built with React for the front-end and Python-Django on the back end. This application suggests heat levels for hot chicken orders that match the user's heat tolerance which is determined on registration. Over time users will rate the many heat levels across Nashville's more popular Hot Chicken restaurants creating an index of averages.

# Are You Going?

https://github.com/leorondeau/are-you-going

"Are you going?" is a mobile first events application in a simple easy to read format built with React. Each user has their own specific data that they can view as well as a limited amount of data on other user's profiles. It is a full CRUD app where users can create their own event as well as add other user's events to curate their own event schedule.

#### **CONTACT**

701-871-1056 leorondeau2020@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/leo-rondeau github.com/leorondeau Leorondeau.io

#### **ABOUT**

Before I entered into software development I worked as a songwriter and singer, touring the US and internationally. After the world came to a stop in 2020 I started coding and enjoyed it so much I decided to attend Nashville Software School. I've always sought new experiences and challenges that keep my mind energized with unknown possibilities.

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

- · React, JavaScript
- · Python, Django
- PostgreSQL
- · CSS, Bootstrap-React
- · HTML
- · Git, Github
- · Adobe XD

#### **EDUCATION**

Nashville Software School

- Full Stack Developer Program,
  2021
- Mastering SQL for Developers,
  2021

North Dakota State University

• BS in Construction Engineering, 2003

# **Work History**

# Songwriter

Sept 2009-Mar 2020

Wrote songs and performed them throughout the United States, UK, Europe and Australia. I released multiple albums of my own material and had my songs recorded by other artists.

- · Booked domestic tours and coordinated with agents abroad
- · Managed band personnel
- · Merchandise designed and produced
- · Online sales and delivery
- · Coordinated video and recording projects

## **Beer Distributor**

Jul 2012-Oct 2017

Kept track of hundreds of accounts in Austin TX for line maintenance and product delivery

- Organized routes for maximum efficiency of time and resources
- · Serviced clients to insure great tasting beer
- · Coordinated with managers for responsive delivery
- · Acted as an ambassador for great German and Czech style beers

## **Production Scheduler**

Oct 2005-May 2009

Master scheduler for all concrete produced and shipped. Ordered material and maximized bed space to follow just in time (JIT) principles and limit onsite storage

- · Coordinated with project managers to ensure on time delivery
- Insured that all products were ready to be shipped on time
- Responded quickly to project schedule changes
- · Kept thorough records of all pieces in every project
- · Produced cost estimates for new projects